Guide to the Birge M. Clark Architectural Records and Personal Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Birge M. Clark architectural records and personal papers
1919-1990
SC0823
Clark, Birge M. (Birge Malcolm), 1893-
12 Linear feet (29 boxes)
The collection has been organized into 4 series. Series 1, Office Files, contains chronological correspondence files, 1921-1979; project files containing correspondence, contracts, financial documents, notes, small-scale drawings, memoranda, and other materials, 1924-1990; and files on administrative matters, articles and talks on Palo Alto's architectural history, and other professional activities. Series 2 consists of photographs and slides of finished projects (homes, schools, municipal buildings, and businesses), 1927-1977. Series 3 contains specifications and some drawings and plans. Series 4, Personal Papers, includes files from architecture classes Clark taught at Stanford containing syllabi, exams, informational materials, lectures, and correspondence, 1950-1972; files from Stanford's Class of 1914 fundraising efforts, 1977-79; copies of his two memoirs, 1971 and 1982; and other miscellaneous papers.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The collection was given to the Stanford University Archives by the estate of Birge M. Clark in 1996.
Information about Access
The class roll book at the end of Series 4 is restricted. Otherwise the collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Associated Materials
Architectural drawings by Clark and his partners are housed in SC0838, Birge M.Clark Architectural Drawings.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Birge M. Clark earned his A.B. in graphic art at Stanford in 1914 and his degree in architecture at Columbia in 1917. After his service as a balloon observer during World War I, he returned to Palo Alto and began his practice as an architect. He designed many homes and businesses in Palo Alto, including the Post Office, the Community Center, and the Hewlett-Packard plant. His contributions to Stanford's architecture include the Seeley G. Mudd Chemistry Building and the John Stauffer Chemical Laboratories.
Description of the Collection
This collection of papers has been organized into 4 series. Series 1, Office Files, contains chronological correspondence files, 1921-1979; project files containing correspondence, contracts, financial documents, notes, small-scale drawings, memoranda, and other materials, 1924-1990; and files on administrative matters, articles and talks on Palo Alto's architectural history, and other professional activities. Series 2 consists of photographs and slides of finished projects (homes, schools, municipal buildings, and businesses), 1927-1977. Series 3 contains specifications and some drawings and plans. Series 4, Personal Papers, includes files from architecture classes Clark taught at Stanford containing syllabi, exams, informational materials, lectures, and correspondence, 1950-72; files from Stanford's Class of 1914 fundraising efforts, 1977-1979; copies of his two memoirs, 1971 and 1982; and other miscellaneous papers.
Access Terms
Clark, Birge M. (Birge Malcolm), 1893-; Architects.; Architecture, Domestic--California; Architecture--Study and teaching.; Palo Alto (Calif.)--History.
Collection Contents
- Office Files, Series 1
  - Correspondence, 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1973 Jan.-July (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1973 Aug.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bills and receipts, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Boy Scout Fire Cirle (#484), 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Branham High School (Campbell Unified School District), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cal-West Communities, correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2.1)
  - Clark (Birge) residence, 1936-1937, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Clark (Birge) residence, cancelled checks, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Crittenden Middle School, Mountain View, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Crittenden Middle School, Mountain View, trellis, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hewlett Packard, AIA National Awards Program, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6.1)
  - Hewlett Packard, building 32, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hoover Houses (series of 5 on SU campus), 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jordan Junior High School (#432), 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Jordan (David Starr) residence (#186), 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kimber residence, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Old Mountain View High School, appraisal, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Palo Alto Community Theater (#367), 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Palo Alto Community Theater (#374), 1933-1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Palo Alto Post Office (#364), 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - San Jose Civic Center, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stern residence (#360), 1931-1939 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Theuerkauf Elementary School, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Color examples for Theuerkauf Elementary School, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Whisman Sports Center, Mountain View, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Whisman School, color examples (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - White Office Building, brochures and ads (Box 3, Folder 10.1)
  - Williams residence, Pebble Beach, CA, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - American Arbitrtion Association - Copple/Hopkins case, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - American Arbitrtion Association - Skykomish/Huber case, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - American Arbitrtion Association - UC Regents/Kump case, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - American Arbitrtion Association - Burkett/Bakke case, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - American Arbitrtion Association - Eagleston/Baxter case, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - American Arbitrtion Association, general correspondence, 1962-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Architect's license (Birge and David), 1934 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Architecture as Related to Citizenship," typescript lecture, circa 1921 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Brochure/Marketing layout, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Campus Homes and Their Inhabitants," outline and text of talk, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Canary v. Trans-Bay, expert witness, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Comments on Norris home, article, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Commercial Buildings in Palo Alto Designed by the Office of Birge M. Clark," typescript text with additional pages on Mrs. Stern and the Community Center, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Commercial buildings in Palo Alto, clippings, 1933-1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Design at Home," text for a talk, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Drowning incident (Mr. Marx), Clark's account of, circa 1939 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Early California architecture, text for talk on, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Exposition home print (Morsman house), Christmas card, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hoover House, correspondence regarding, 1969-1980 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Hoover House, clippings, 1972-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hoover House, historic status, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hoover House - California Historic Landmark Dedication, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - National Defense, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Notes on old College Terrace and old Mayfield,", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Palo Alto homes, list and correspondence regarding, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Palo Alto Savings and Loan Association, 1965-1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Palo Alto Savings and Loan Association, 1950-1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Palo Alto Savings and Loan Association, two reports, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photo records, miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Residences in Palo Alto and Stanford Designed by the Office of Birge M. Clark,", circa 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Residences on Stanford campus, lists (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Veterans' Building (Palo Alto) - Landmark Dedication, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Veterans' Building (Palo Alto) - Citizens' Advisory Committee report, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Veterans' Building (Palo Alto) - Citizens' Advisory Committee, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Veterans' Building (Palo Alto) - background on Julia Morgan (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Veterans' Building (Redwood City) - Historic Resource Report prepared by Diana J. Painter, 2010 August (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Architectural Digest, Vol. 7, No. 2, with several illustrations of buildings by Clark, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Index cards to architectural drawings, group 1: Palo Alto and Stanford (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Index cards to architectural drawings, group 2: all other locations (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Photographs and Slides, Series 2
  - Photographs, Subseries 1
    - Dormitory at Menlo College [label missing]. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton (Box 1)
    - Ingold residence, Hillsborough, view of house from garden. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Ingold residence, Hillsborough, view in patio. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Mikel residence, Piedmont, view of house from patio. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Ingold residence, Hillsborough, view of patio entrance detail. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Mikel residence, Piedmont, interior view of stairhall. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Mikel residence, Piedmont, entrance facade. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Mikel residence, Piedmont, entrance doorway. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Menlo School, El Camino dormitory, view under cloister. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Norris residence, grilled doorway. Label from Exhibition of Architecture 1929, De Young Museum, San Francisco. / Crandall, Berton (Box 1)
    - Store buildings for Hare, Brewer & Clark, Palo Alto. Label from Exhibition of Architecture 1929, De Young Museum, San Francisco. / Crandall, Berton (Box 1)
    - Group of Ramona Street stores (538-542), Palo Alto. Label from Exhibition of Architecture 1929, De Young Museum, San Francisco. / Crandall, Berton (Box 1)
    - 436-452 University Avenue, Palo Alto, Varsity Theater facade included. / Crandall, Berton, 1927 (Box 1)
    - Ruth Stern residence, rear view / Waters, George (Box 2)
    - Alta Mesa Cemetery. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1933 (Box 2)
    - Alta Mesa Cemetery (interior view of building). Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1933 (Box 2)
    - Palo Alto Medical Clinic, Children's Waiting Room. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton (Box 2)
    - Palo Alto Medical Clinic, interior. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Residence, Charles and Kathleen Norris, Palo Alto, CA / Crandall, Berton (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Louis Stern residence, Miss Ruth Stern residence. Joint patio / Waters, George (Box 2)
    - Miss Ruth Stern residence, living room fireplace. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Stern residence on Cowper, Palo Alto, garden. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Lucie Stern residence on Cowper, Palo Alto. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Louis Stern residence on Cowper, Palo Alto, front elevation. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Louis Stern residence (walled garden between residences of Mrs. Louis Stern & Miss Ruth Stern). Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton (Box 2)
    - Palo Alto Community Theater [interior]. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton (Box 2)
    - Palo Alto Community Theater Foyer. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton (Box 2)
    - Dental offices for Dr. Hugh David Phillips. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton (Box 2)
    - Palo Alto Medical Cinic Interior. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects. / Crandall, Berton (Box 2)
    - Lucie Stern Residence, Palo Alto. / Waters, George, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Louis Stern Residence, Palo Alto. / Waters, George, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Abrams residence (Stanford University?) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brooks, Julia Fox, residence, 526 Coleridge, Palo Alto (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Browne, A. A., residence, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cal-West Sunset Park of Sunnyvale (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cal-West Sunset Park of Walnut Creek (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Camden High School (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Campbell High School (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Clark, Birge - residence (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Clark, Stromquist & Potter offices (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Clark, Stromquist & Sandstrom offices (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Coleridge Street (470 & 544) residences, Palo Alto (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Crandall's, Palo Alto, circa 1930 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Del Mar High School, photos by Larry Hill (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dunker, John A., residence, Palo Alto, 1927, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dunn, Dr., residence - prints (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Dunn, Dr., residence - negatives (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - El Carmelo School (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Ellis, Gertrude M., residence, Palo Alto, circa 1928 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Escuela School, Mountain View - negatives (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Escuela School, Mountain View - prints (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Fairmeadow Elementary School (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Fairfield Senior Center, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Fleishhacker residence, Western Homes Award Competition, prints (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Fleishhacker residence, Western Homes Award Competition, negatives (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Garland School (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Goodenough, Wells P., residence, Palo Alto (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Gousha Company (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Green Gables Elementary School (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Hapgood residence, Palo Alto, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Hewlett-Packard prints, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hewlett-Packard, negatives and color transparencies (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Historical, 1906 earthquake damage at Stanford University (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Historical and miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Home Dairy (Mayfield) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry house, Stanford, construction (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry house, Stanford, exteriors (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry house, Stanford, interiors (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry house, Stanford, model of (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Hoover Pavilion, prints (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Hoover Pavilion, prints (2) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Hoover Pavilion, negatives (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Ingold residence (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Italian historical (Florence, Pisa, Venice) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Jungeblut, Dr. C. W., residence, Stanford, circa 1928 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Kimber residence (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Laumeister residence, Webster & University (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Lee, Mrs. R. V. A., residence, Palo Alto, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Loma Vista School, prints and negatives, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Loma Vista School, prints, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Magna Engineering Company, exteriors, color transparencies (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Magna Engineering Company, prints (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Mayfield Depot Garage (Box 4, Folder 22.1)
    - Medico-Dental Building, Palo Alto, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Menlo School for Boys (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Merner, Mrs. D. W., 5 houses on Middlefield (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Mikel, Rossiter L., residence (Piedmont) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Mountain View Board Offices, color transparency (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Mountain View Senior Center (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Norris (Charles and Kathleen) residence (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Norris (Charles and Kathleen) negatives of personal photographs (Silver Wedding anniversary April 1934 and Castilleja graduation May 1935), 1934-35 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Ohlones School (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ortega (Meadow Park) School (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Palo Alto business, unidentified (Box 5, Folder 2.1)
    - Palo Alto Community Center (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Palo Alto Elementary Schools (composite image) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Palo Alto Police Department (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Palo Alto Post Office, 1932 and n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Palo Alto Senior Center (former Police Dept.), circa 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Palo Alto Senior Center (former Police Dept.), model for (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Palo Alto Times (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Palo Verde Elementary School (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - President Hotel, Palo Alto (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Prospect High School (Campbell Union H.S. District) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Quinby residence, Edgewood Drive, Palo Alto - negatives and transparencies (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Quinby residence, Edgewood Drive, Palo Alto - prints, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Ramona Street scenes, circa 1930-70 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Ramona Street stores, Palo Alto, 1929 and n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Residences, unidentified [originally marked "own work"], undated (Box 5, Folder 16.1)
    - Reynolds, Dr. Harry B., residence, Palo Alto, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Richter store, Palo Alto (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Roos Brothers, Palo Alto (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Saier, Dr., beach house at Capitola (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Seeley G. Mudd Chemistry Building, Stanford University, 1975-77 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Snedden residence, Amherst Avenue, Palo Alto (including Mr. & Mrs. Snedden in one), 1948 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Speidel residence, Edwood Drive, Palo Alto (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Stanford Auto Company (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Stanford University food services building, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Stanford University Medical School (San Francisco), Stern Research Lab, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Stauffer Chemistry Buildings, Stanford University (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Stromquist, Walter (portraits), 1936, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Stromquist residence (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Strub, Dr. Charles H., University Avenue stores, Palo Alto, circa 1928 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Syntex Laboratories - prints, 1967, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Syntex Laboratories - negatives (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Syntex Production Building, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - University Avenue (300 block) stores, Palo Alto (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - University Avenue (423, 425), Palo Alto, circa 1930 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Van Auken Elementary School, Palo Alto, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ventura Elementary School (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Veterans Building, Redwood City, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Wall Street Journal, Palo Alto Plant (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Washington High School, circa 1935 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Watkins-Johnson Co., Palo Alto (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Waverly Street stores, Palo Alto, circa 1930 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Wells Fargo Bank, Palo Alto (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Westmont High School (Campbell UHSD), 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - White, C.A., residence, Los Altos (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - White (Howard J.) Office Building, 1960-1964 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Williams Coninuation High School (Campbell UHSD) (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Winterburn, J. C., residence (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Unidentified prints and negatives (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Unidentified damaged negatives (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Abrams residence (Stanford) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - [Blackburn residence] 570 Coleridge, Palo Alto (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Clark (Dan) residence (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Colerdige #544, residence (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Davis residence (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Ellis (G.) residence (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Gurley residence (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Hamilton residence, Los Altos (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Hapgood residence (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Hoover residence on Stanford campus (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Hoover houses (5 by Mrs. Hoover) on Stanford campus (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Ingold residence, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Kinney residence (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Kirk residence (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Lovell residences (555 Lowell and 559 Seale) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Lucie Stern Community Center, Palo Alto, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Marino residence (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Palo Alto Building & Loan (interior) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Palo Alto police / fire building (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Philippines building (San Francisco) (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Proctor residence (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Reynolds (Harry) residence, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Seeley G. Mudd Chemistry Building, Stanford [printing negative] (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Stanford Auto Company (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Strong residence (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Sullivan (J. T.) residence (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified exteriors (residences) (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Unidentified interiors (residences) (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - University Avenue, 300 block, Palo Alto (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - University Realty (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Wellgould residence (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Whitling residence (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Photograph albums (3) of Spanish style residences (not all designed by Clark), circa 1930; Album (Box 8)
    - Photograph album of English style residences, circa 1930; Album (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Photograph album of stores, circa 1930; Album (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Photograph album of residences [probably "Spanish" but original label is illegible], circa 1930; Album (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Slides of schools (A-J), model for Ampex, Clark Stromquist & Potter office, Eastman Kodak, and Hewlett-Packard (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Slides of schools (L-W), Veterans Building, Watkins-Johnson, and unidentified images (buildings, aerials, and sites) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Slides of business signs in Palo Alto, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Slides, Subseries 2
    - Addison School (Box 1)
    - Ampex (model only) (Box 1)
    - Benj. Bubb School (Box 1)
    - Benj. Cory School (Box 1)
    - Campbell High (Box 1)
    - Carlmont (Box 1)
    - Centerville School (Box 1)
    - Clark, Stromquist & Potter office (Box 1)
    - Costano-Kump Ravenswood (Box 1)
    - Crescent Park (Box 1)
    - Cubberley High School (Box 1)
    - Cupertino School (Box 1)
    - Doyle School, Cupertino (Box 1)
    - Eastman Kodak (Box 1)
    - El Carmelo School (Box 1)
    - Escuela, Mt. View (Box 1)
    - Fairmeadow (Box 1)
    - Glenmoor School (Box 1)
    - Green Gables (Box 1)
    - Greendell (Box 1)
    - H. D. Silva School (Box 1)